<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[IEEE Compute | The Blog]]></title><description><![CDATA[Official Blog of IEEE Compute]]></description><link>https://IEEECompute.github.io/blog</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2016 05:40:54 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://IEEECompute.github.io/blog/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Self Driving Buses Hit The Road In Helsinki]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="sect3">
<h4 id="_apoorva_jain_content_designer_team_ieee_compute">Apoorva Jain, Content Designer, Team IEEE Compute</h4>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>After Google’s self driving cars, the latest self driven automobiles that can be seen on the roads of Helsinki are the minibuses. These small electric buses were developed by a French company EasyMile which is a joint venture between two other French companies, automaker Ligier and robotics firm Robosoft. These buses will be able to achieve a maximum speed of 25 miles per hour, but are being driven at 7 miles per hour during the trial period and can accommodate up to nine passengers at a time.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><span class="image"><img src="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/money/dam/assets/160818123136-self-driving-bus-2-780x439.png" alt="160818123136 self driving bus 2 780x439.png"></span></p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>These buses are being deployed to carry passenger between two busy stations in the city’s waterfront Harnesaari district. A driver is stationed on board in case of an emergency.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>This project aims to make Helsinki a carless zone within a few years. The city, which already has a well established transport system, is also developing an on demand mobility program, which would digitalize the booking procedure with the help of an integrated mobile app.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The buses will be launched in two more Finnish cities, namely, Espoo and Tampere later this year. They will be under a trial period this winter, but would join the fleet in spring.</p>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>https://IEEECompute.github.io/blog/2016/10/07/Self-Driving-Buses-Hit-The-Road-In-Helsinki.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://IEEECompute.github.io/blog/2016/10/07/Self-Driving-Buses-Hit-The-Road-In-Helsinki.html</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Compute]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Modular Mobile Technology]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="sect3">
<h4 id="_adityaraj_s_content_designer_team_ieee_compute">Adityaraj S, Content Designer, Team IEEE Compute</h4>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>A bunch of people at google thought, maybe the user does not require to dump his current phone to get amazing new features of the newly developed phones. They thought, why not we make the different components of the phone such as the speakers, the screens all into different modules and the just assemble them together on a single core structural frame. This laid the foundation for project Ara.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><span class="image"><img src="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/HyUQ4uD9Y3U/maxresdefault.jpg" alt="maxresdefault.jpg"></span></p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The Project Ara was launched by google in the fall of 2015. This idea purely caters to the urge of personalising one’s smart phone. It’s the concept of modular phone, wherein, the user has the freedom to attach various components of the phone such as cameras, screens, speakers etc. of different specifications to their phones. The core components like the processors, GPU and Antenna clusters are fabricated into the frame of the phone. The contact points are places across the frame to make these core components accessible by the accessory modules (camera, speaker, screen module etc.). This creates a sea of options for the user to configure their phone as per their convenience.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The independent hardware modules of the phone would be made available in the market to buy from. As an example, if a user wishes to capture some detailed photos, he can just simply slide out the existing camera module from his phone and replace it with another camera module with higher resolution available in the market. This enables the user to greatly personalise his phone as per his requirements.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Electronic waste possesses a huge problem now a days. The Project Ara could also be seen as an attempt at reducing the electronic waste generated by discarded phones. With the conventional phones, the only way to stay updated with latest mobile computing technology is to replace the existing phone with a new one, but with Project Ara, user can stay updated to latest technology by just replacing the previous functional module with the latest functional module. This reduces the cost of upgradation as well and is better on carbon footprint.</p>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>https://IEEECompute.github.io/blog/2016/10/07/Modular-Mobile-Technology.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://IEEECompute.github.io/blog/2016/10/07/Modular-Mobile-Technology.html</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Compute]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[History Of IEEE Compute]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div id="preamble">
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="https://scontent.fmaa1-2.fna.fbcdn.net/v/t1.0-9/12003416_1042580775772604_429239502955523407_n.jpg?oh=7e8cad82b91a89d0091ccd7e6ffed4e5&oe=5862120A" alt="12003416 1042580775772604 429239502955523407 n.jpg?oh=7e8cad82b91a89d0091ccd7e6ffed4e5&amp;oe=5862120A">
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect3">
<h4 id="_know_how_we_started">Know how we started&#8230;&#8203;</h4>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The IEEE Compute Newsletter is the brainchild of the IEEE India Council CS SAC. Since its conception in 2015, when the first volume hit the stands for all the curious minds in India, the IEEE Compute Newsletter has been serving as a means to communicate the events, trends and developments in the computer industry to its readers. Two very successful issues of the Newsletter have been released with the inspiring hard work and commitment shown by the teams working for the Newsletter. These teams are unique in their diversity, with members from different streams, universities, and states, working together, untiringly, to bring the newsletter to its communicative potential.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Past newsletters contained brief accounts of the various activities and events organized by the different sections of IEEE, throughout India. Topics ranging from Quantum Computing to Security in Cloud Computing were covered in the past, in a comprehensible yet concise manner, making it easy for readers from all over the country to understand the concepts without over-complicating the subject matter. Aside from technological innovations, the newsletters also contained interviews with inspiring personalities for readers to derive motivation from, to excel in their endeavors.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Despite its past success, the Compute team knows that there is always more room for improvement. With new worker bees joining the growing beehive that is the Newsletter team, efforts are being made to come out with more captivating, engaging and ultimately stimulating articles for readers. Putting out relevant and stirring content has always been a priority for the Compute team and this issue of the IEEE Compute Newsletter aims to fulfill these goals and more.</p>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>https://IEEECompute.github.io/blog/2016/10/05/History-Of-IEEE-Compute.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://IEEECompute.github.io/blog/2016/10/05/History-Of-IEEE-Compute.html</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Compute]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>